Mary Coulling Papers, 1806-1997 WLU Coll. 0248
Special Collections, Washington and Lee University
Special Collections and Archives, James G. Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University
Mary Coulling Papers 1806-1997
Special Collections and Archives, James G. Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University
248
This collection consists of 169 items.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Contents List
- The Lee Girls
  - Control Folder (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Arlington (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Baltimore Association 1848-1851 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Canal and Boat Locks 1865 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Coulling brochure on Custis & Lee families 1997 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Extras - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Family trees (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Houses & other places associated with Lees (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Houses - maps of locations (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Lee, GWC - Letters & recollections 1862-1912 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Lee, GWC - will (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Lee, Mildred - about her & her friends (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Lee, R.E., Jr. - Letters 1861-1863 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Lee, R.E. III - info (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Lee, WHF - 1853, 1856 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Lexington & Environs (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Richmond, diary extract 1864-1865 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Tudor Place (Box-folder 1:20)
  - White House (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Custis, G. W. P. - Slaves (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Custis Bible (Box-folder 2:23)
  - Lee, Agnes - Letters (transcripts & copies to 1865) (Box-folder 2:24)
  - Lee, Agnes - Letters to 1865 continued (Box-folder 2:25)
  - Lee, Agnes - 1865-1873 (Box-folder 2:26)
  - Lee, Agnes - Journal (Box-folder 2:27)
  - Lee, Agnes - Williams, William Orton and Williams, Markie (Box-folder 2:28)
  - Lee, Agnes - Letters (transcripts & copies) (Box-folder 2:29)
  - Lee, Agnes - Letters, continued (Box-folder 2:30)
  - Lee, Agnes - Letters, 1848 from R. E. Lee (Box-folder 2:31)
  - Lee, Agnes - Burial spot (Box-folder 2:32)
  - Lee, Agnes - Death (Box-folder 2:33)
  - Lee, Agnes - Memorial Service (Box-folder 2:34)
  - Lee, Mary C. (Mrs. R. E.) - Letters (transcripts, copies) to 1865 (Box-folder 2:35)
  - Lee, Mary C. (Mrs. R. E.) - Letters (transcripts, copies) to 1865, continued (Box-folder 2:36)
  - Lee, Mary C. (Mrs. R. E.) - 1865, death in 1873 (Box-folder 2:37)
  - Lee, Mary C. (Mrs. R. E.) - Recipe (Box-folder 2:38)
  - Lee, Mary C. (daughter) - Letters (transcripts & copies) to 1870 (Box-folder 2:39)
  - Lee, Mary C. (daughter) - later years (Box-folder 2:40)
  - Lee, Mary C. - Estate 1918 (Box-folder 2:41)
  - Lee, Mary C. - Index to scrapbook (Box-folder 2:42)
  - Lee, Mildred - Letters (transcripts & copies) to 1870 (Box-folder 2:43)
  - Lee, Mildred - Letters to 1870, continued (Box-folder 2:44)
  - Lee, Mildred - 1870-1905 (Box-folder 2:45)
  - Lee, Mildred - 1870-1905, continued (Box-folder 2:46)
  - Lee, Mildred - MacDonald, Marshall (Box-folder 2:47)
  - Lee Girls - Chronology 1865-1918 (Box-folder 2:48)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Height and Weight (Box-folder 2:49)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Humor (Box-folder 2:50)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Letters (transcripts & copies) to 1861 (Box-folder 2:51)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Letters 1861-1865 (Box-folder 2:52)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Letters, Appom., 1870 October (Box-folder 2:53)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Silver of the Family (Box-folder 2:54)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Will copy to 1870 (Box-folder 2:55)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Final Illness & Death 1870 (Box-folder 2:56)
  - In this box Mary Coulling's note cards for The Lee Girls, 4 files (Box 3)
    See also Box 6, pt. 2 - Articles, Theses, etc. on Mary Coulling's Subjects & Speeches on the Lees
- Margaret Junkin Preston Research
  Letters and other materials - copies and transcripts - arranged in chronological order.
  - CONTROL and lists of letters that Mrs. Coulling xeroxed (Box-folder 4:1)
  - 1806, 1819 - Julia R. Junkin (Mrs. George) (Box-folder 4:2)
  - 1820 - Julia R. Junkin (Mrs. George) (Box-folder 4:3)
  - 1821 - Julia R. Junkin (Mrs. George) (Box-folder 4:4)
  - 1822-23 - Julia R. Junkin (Mrs. George) (Box-folder 4:5)
  - 1824 - Letters from George and Julia R. Junkin. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - 1825-1826 - Julia R. Junkin (Box-folder 4:7)
  - 1828-1829 - Julia R. Junkin (Box-folder 4:8)
  - 1830-1831 - Julia R. And George Junkin (Box-folder 4:9)
  - 1832 - Julia R. Junkin - First appearance of Margaret (March 20, June 4). (Box-folder 4:10)
  - 1833-1834 - Julia R., George, and Margaret Junkin (Box-folder 4:11)
  - 1835 - Julia R. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - 1836-37 Julia R. Also David X. Junkin (August 19). (Box-folder 4:13)
  - 1838 - Julia R. Junkin - Poem by Margaret (Box-folder 4:14)
  - 1839 - Margaret, poem and letters often to Helen Dickey, her cousin. Letter of Eleanor Junkin. (Box-folder 4:15)
  - 1840 - Letters of Eleanor, George, David X., Margaret, Julia Junkin. (Box-folder 4:16)
  - 1841 - Letters of Julia R., Margaret, Eleanor, George Junkin. (Box-folder 4:17)
  - 1842-43 - Eleanor, George, Julia R. Junkin. (Box-folder 4:18)
  - 1844-45 - Eleanor, Margaret, Julia R., George Junkin. (Box-folder 4:19)
  - 1846 - Margaret, Ellie, Julia, George Junkin. (Box-folder 4:20)
  - 1847 - Julia, George Junkin. (Box-folder 4:21)
  - 1848 - Julia, George Junkin. (Box-folder 4:22)
  - 1849 - Ellie, George, Julia Margaret Junkin. (Box-folder 4:23)
  - 1850-1952 - Margaret, Julia R. David X. Junkin. (Box-folder 4:24)
  - 1853 - Julia, Margaret, Poem to Ellie Junkin; Jackson, Thomas Jonathan Oct. 19, Nov. 30 (Box-folder 4:25)
  - 1854 - George, Julia R. Young Julie Junkin, Margaret to T J Jackson Dec. 19. Ellie died in 1854. Sermon. Also Julia R. Junkin. (Box-folder 4:26)
  - 1855 - Correspondence between TJ Jackson and Margaret (Box-folder 4:27)
  - 1856 - Margaret, Julia Junkin; Fishburn, George and T J Jackson. (Box-folder 4:28)
  - 1857-1858 - T J Jackson, Margaret, George (Box-folder 4:29)
  - 1859-1860 - T J Jackson, George (Box-folder 4:30)
  - 1861 -1862 - T J Jackson to Margaret; George, Margaret, David X.; August 21, 1862 letter from A. Lincoln to Margaret; Maggie Junkin Preston to Rebecca Glasgow, May 27, 1862 (Box-folder 4:31)
  - 1863 - Letters from T J Jackson shortly before his death (Box-folder 4:32)
  - 1864 - Account of Hunter's Raid. (Box-folder 4:33)
  - 1866-1870 - Mary Anna Jackson and Margaret Junkin Preston; Beginning of Margaret Junkin Preston's correspondence with Paul H. Hayne. (Box-folder 4:34)
  - 1871-1872 - MJP/Hayne (Box-folder 4:35)
  - 1873-1875 - MJP/Hayne (Box-folder 4:36)
  - 1876-1880 - Two originals to Louisa Baxter from MJP. MJP/Hayne (Box-folder 4:37)
  - 1881-1884 - MJP/Hayne; 1882 - JTL Preston's poem to MJP on their 25th Anniversary. (Box-folder 4:38)
  - 1885-1886 - MJP/Hayne; Paul H. Hayne dies; MJP to T N Page and to Mrs. Hayne. (Box-folder 4:39)
  - 1887-1889 - MJP to a Prof. Bakervill (& others) (Box-folder 4:40)
  - 1891-1894 - Three originals included MJP. (Box-folder 4:41)
  - N.D. (Box-folder 4:42)
  - Coulling; index to the poetry of MJP (Box-folder 5:43)
  - Poems in Manuscripts (copies) (Box-folder 5:44)
  - Centennial Poem printed (Box-folder 5:44a)
  - Scrapbook "at J. Preston's" (Box-folder 5:45)
  - Scrapbook 1870-1880, 1-69 (Box-folder 5:46)
  - Scrapbook 1870-1880, 70-144 (Box-folder 5:47)
  - Poetry Notebook 1837-1840 (Box-folder 5:48)
  - Notebook II 1840-1852 (Box-folder 5:49)
  - Scrapbook - stories, poems 1850-1857 (Box-folder 5:50)
  - Sketchbook 1844 + (Box-folder 5:51)
  - Idea notebook - Lexington (Box-folder 5:52)
  - Index to Notebooks 1837-1840, 1840-1850 (Box-folder 5:53)
  - Indexes to Scrapbooks and Sketchbook (Box-folder 5:54)
  - Index to Scrapbooks 1870s and 1880s (Box-folder 5:55)
  - Wee Daire (Box-folder 5:56)
  - Poems not in scrapbooks or collected books. (Box-folder 5:57)
  - Poems not in scrapbooks or collected books. (Box-folder 5:58)
  - Essays by MJP. (Box-folder 5:59)
  - Reviews not in scrapbooks. (Box-folder 5:60)
  - List of reviews. (Box-folder 5:61)
  - Stories not in scrapbooks. (Box-folder 5:62)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 5:63)
  - Photographs and prints (Box-folder 5:64)
  - Junkin genealogy (Box-folder 5:65)
  - Miller family notes (Box-folder 5:66)
  - Quick Reference - chronology, family connections, dates - Proceedings of the Northumberland County Historical Society (Box-folder 5:67)
  - Fishburne, Julia Junkin (Box-folder 6:68)
  - Junkin, George (Dr.) (Box-folder 6:69)
  - Junkin, George - Biography (Box-folder 6:70)
  - Junkin, George - Eschatological Vision (Box-folder 6:71)
  - Junkin, George (David X's son) (Box-folder 6:72)
  - Junkin, George Plot (Box-folder 6:73)
  - Preston, J. T. L. - Data (Box-folder 6:74)
  - Preston, J. T. L. - Diary (Box-folder 6:75)
  - Preston, J. T. L. - Diary (Box-folder 6:76)
  - Preston, J. T. L. - General Information (Box-folder 6:77)
  - Preston, J. T. L. - Family - Photo (Box-folder 6:78)
  - Preston, J. T. L. - Talk to Franklin Society (Box-folder 6:79)
  - Preston, J. T. L. - VMI Files (Box-folder 6:80)
  - Preston, Margaret Junkin - Comments on - to 1906 (Box-folder 6:81)
  - Preston, Margaret Junkin - Comments on - after 1906 (Box-folder 6:82)
  - Preston, Margaret Junkin - Misc. (Box-folder 6:83)
  - Preston Genealogy (Box-folder 6:84)
  - M. A. Thesis, 1933, by John Hugh Grey, Jr. (Box-folder 6:85)
  - Student Paper on MJP by John A. F. Hall, Jr. '51 (Box-folder 6:86)
  - "Miscellaneous" (Box-folder 6:87)
  - "Southern Magazines" article (Box-folder 6:88)
  - Women Writers - Articles on (Box-folder 6:89)
  - Speech "Maggie and the Major" (Box-folder 6:90)
  - Speech "Margaret Junkin Preston and Her Times" (Box-folder 6:91)
  - Speech MJP "Lexington's First Supermom" (Box-folder 6:92)
  - Speech " Poetess of the South" (Box-folder 6:93)
  - Speech "Tie That Binds" (Box-folder 6:94)
  - Speech "Well-Used Library of a Nineteenth Century Southern Litterateur" (Box-folder 6:95)
  - Library of Margaret Junkin Preston (Box-folder 6:96)
  - Lee Speeches - "The Distaff Connection" (Box-folder 6:97)
  - Lee Speeches - "George Washington and the Custis and Lee Families" (Box-folder 6:98)
  - Lee Speeches - "The Domesticated Robert E. Lee" (Box-folder 6:99)
  - Lee Speeches - "Robert E. Lee's Views on the Education of Women" (Box-folder 6:100)
  - Lee Speeches - R. E. Lee: Family Man" (Box-folder 6:101)
  - Lee Speeches - "Heritage of R. E. Lee" (Box-folder 6:102)
  - Lee Speeches - "Marse Robert's Humor" (Box-folder 6:103)
  - Lee Speeches - On the Anniversary of Lee's Death (Box-folder 6:104)
  - Lee Speeches - (women) (Box-folder 6:105)
  - Lee Speeches - (women) (Box-folder 6:106)
  - Lee Speeches - "The Lee Girls and the Folks Who Lived at Tudor Place" (Box-folder 6:107)
  - Lee Speeches - The Lee Women - War - Home Front" (Box-folder 6:108)
  - Lee Speeches - "Robert E. Lee's Daughters and the Legacy of the Civil War" (Box-folder 6:109)
  - Lee Speeches - Nicknames, Cats, and Catsup Bottles" (Box-folder 6:110)
  - Mary Coulling's research cards for Margaret Junkin Preston research (Box 7)